Khalid Abdikarim Mohmed

Mogadishu, Somalia



qeys80@gmail.com



+252615803737



linkedin.com/in/khalid-abdikarim-mohamed-5a9a42213

Summary

A Software Engineer with experience working in programming, software development, and consulting. Holds comprehensive technical capability skills and strong knowledge of programming, software, and website development. Dedicated to meeting customer requirements with innovative solutions that maximize efficiency and exceed capability targets.

Experience



Technical Support Engineer

Faruq Public Notary

Apr 2017 - Jan 2019 (1 year 10 months)

Assisted Staff with a diagnosis of software and hardware issues and concerns.

Encouraged timely and relevant upgrades for clients' products as necessary.

Investigated incidents caused by malicious activities and identify false positives.

Perform initial installation of operating systems.

Reviewed procedures and made recommendations to management to streamline operations.



Network Technician

SomStar(ISP)

Mar 2013 - Feb 2017 (4 years)

Provided network support for business and residential clients

Performed troubleshooting and equipment diagnostics in order to resolve connectivity issues

Set up new networking systems designed to suit the clients' needs and budget

Installed and configured computer hardware and software, optimized network performance, and created firewalls that prevented access to unauthorized internet content

Provided troubleshooting and repair as needed

Education

Universiti Putra Malaysia

Master's degree, Computer Software Engineering

Sep 2019 - Sep 2021

During this period, I have learned different courses required to be a Master of Software Engineering. The most important thing you will learn first is how to conduct research as the university focuses on research. In University Putra Malaysia (UPM), students have to come up with a research project in each subject to pass these courses. In addition, during my study, our research paper has been accepted for visual presentation at the International Conference on Engineering Technology (ICET 2021), and

later accepted for publication in IOPscience Conference Series (SCOPUS-indexed). Therefore, this experience helped me to gain extensive experience in research.

Simad University

Computer Science and Information Technology

Sep 2011 - Sep 2015

This is where my journey of studying computer science has started and it really provided me with the tools that I needed to choose the right direction and successfully completed my first bachelor degree in computer science

Al-imam ibnukhuzeyma

High School

Aug 2008 - May 2011

I have graduated from this school starting from my primary to secondary.

Licenses & Certifications

Routing switching and wireless networking - Simad University

English Certificate: ELS Selangor-Malaysia - (In this college, i have gained my English certificate which is equivalent to 6 ILTS score. this certificate was required in order to start my master's degree.)

Skills

Research • Teamwork • Agile & Waterfall Methodologies • Front-end Development • Web Development • React.js • JavaScript • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • Git • HTML

Honors & Awards

Best paper award - 5th international conference on engineering technology (ICET)

Oct 2021

The International Conference on Information Technology (ICIT2021) aims to exchange and share their experiences and research results in all aspects of information technology, software, computer application and other related areas through oral and poster presentation. our paper has won one of the best paper in the 5th international conference on engineering technology (ICET).